<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
    Each calendar year, HRSA Health Center Program awardees and look-alikes are required to report a core set of information, including data on patient characteristics, services provided, clinical processes and health outcomes, patients' use of services, staffing, costs, and revenues as part of a standardized reporting system known as the Uniform Data System (UDS). The UDS is a standard data set that is reported annually and provides consistent information about health centers. 
    It is the source of non duplicated data for the entire scope of services included in the grant or designation for the calendar year. HRSA uses UDS data to assess the impact and performance of the Health Center Program, and to promote data-driven quality improvement. The current UDS data does not contain patient level information however through the UDS+ project HRSA intends to collect patient level de-identified data. This new patient level UDS report is called UDS+ report.
  </p>
  
  <a name="business-needs"> </a>
  <h3>Business Needs</h3>
  <br/>
  <p>
  Currently UDS data is submitted using a tabular data format via participating health centers. The submission mechanisms used by the health centers include HRSA hosted portals, sftp and other mechanisms.
  The data submitted is aggregated at the health center sites and is submitted to HRSA's UDS systems
  </p>
  <p>
    Currently UDS data is submitted using a tabular data format via participating health centers. 
    The submission mechanisms include portals, sftp and other mechanisms. 
    The data submitted is aggregated at the sites and is submitted to HRSA's UDS systems and does not have patient level data currently. 
    While this data satisfies the basic reporting, HRSA would like to improve the efficiency, quality and timeliness of the data along with the granularity of the data.
    The granularity of the data should include patient level de-identified data to support the analysis to be performed by BPHC. 
    As part of the UDS+ project, HRSA would like to standardize the data submission protocols, formats and increase the granularity of the data being submitted to support the downstream analysis to be performed. 
  </p>
  <br/>
  <h3>IG Scope</h3>
	<p>
		The following aspects are part of the scope of the project.
		<uL>
        <li>
		Collect standardized UDS data from: 
		<ul><li>health centers that receive federal award funds (“awardees”) under the Health Center Program authorized by section 330 of the Public Health Service (PHS) Act (42 U.S.C. 254b) (“section 330”), as amended (including sections 330(e), (g), (h), and (i))

health centers considered Health Center Program look-alikes. Look-alikes DO NOT receive regular federal funding under section 330 of the PHS Act (although they may receive funding during
public health emergencies, such as COVID-19), but meet the Health Center Program requirements for designation under the program (42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(4)(A)(ii) and 42 U.S.C. 1396d(l)(2)(B)(ii)).
		</li></ul>

<ul><li>health centers funded under the Health Resources and Services Administration’s (HRSA) Bureau of Health Workforce (BHW)
</li></ul>
</li>
<li>Define under what circumstance an EHR system must create and transmit a UDS report to HRSA
</li>

<li>Identify the data elements to be retrieved from the EHR to produce reports</li>
</uL>
	</p>
	<br/>
	<h3>IG Out-Of-Scope</h3>
	<p>
	<ul>
	<li>Validation of the EHR data</li>

    <li>Data captured outside the EHR </li>

    <li>Changes to existing health center workflow or existing data entry</li>

	<li>Policies of the health centers to collect consent for data sharing</li>
	</ul>
	</p>
	<br/>
	<h3>References to Existing Documentation</h3>
	<p>
	<ul>
	<li><a href="https://bphc.hrsa.gov/sites/default/files/bphc/datareporting/pdf/2021-uds-manual.pdf">Uniform Data System 2021 Health Center Data Reporting Requirements Manual</a></li>

    <li><a href="https://bphc.hrsa.gov/sites/default/files/bphc/datareporting/pdf/2021-uds-manual-tables.pdf">Uniform Data System 2021 Health Center Data Reporting Tables</a></li>
	</ul>
	</p>
	<br/>
	<h3>Dependencies on Other IGs</h3>
	<p>
	<ul>
	<li>US Core IG</li>

    <li>Bulk Data Access IG</li>

    <li>QI Core IG</li>
	</ul>
	</p>
</div>
