<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>
    Each calendar year, HRSA Health Center Program awardees and look-alikes are required to report a core set of information, including data on patient characteristics, services provided, clinical processes and health outcomes, patients' use of services, staffing, costs, and revenues as part of a standardized reporting system known as the Uniform Data System (UDS). The UDS is a standard data set that is reported annually and provides consistent information about health centers. 
    It is the source of non duplicated data for the entire scope of services included in the grant or designation for the calendar year. HRSA uses UDS data to assess the impact and performance of the Health Center Program, and to promote data-driven quality improvement. The current UDS data does not contain patient level information however through the UDS+ project HRSA intends to collect patient level de-identified data. This new patient level UDS report is called UDS+ report.
  </p>
  <p>
  This Implementation Guide (IG) defines the specifications by which Health Center Program awardees can report the UDS+ data to HRSA using 
  <ul>
  <li><b>De-identified Patient data using FHIR APIs</b></li>
  </ul>
  </p>
	<a name="technical"> </a>
	<h3>Technical Overview</h3>
	<p>
	Currently UDS data is submitted using a tabular data format via participating health centers. The submission mechanisms include portals, sftp and other mechanisms.
	The data submitted is aggregated at the sites and is submitted to HRSA's UDS systems. In order to improve the efficiency, quality and timeliness of the data, The Bureau of Primary Health Care (BPHC) will transition most of the UDS data to de-identified patient-level data.
	This modified patient level UDS report is called UDS+. 
    In the context of the IG, there are two primary actors namely 
    <ul>
    <li>Health Centers</li>
    <li>HRSA</li>
    </ul>
  </p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <p>
    The main sections of this IG are:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="background.html">Background</a> - Provides business context for the implementation guide and information that implementers should be
      familiar with before reading the remainder of the IG. This identifies the context of the IG and the various reporting mechanisms.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="usecases.html">Use Cases</a> - Defines the  use case, workflows, actors and systems that will be used for UDS+ reporting.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="dataelements.html">UDS+ Data Elements and FHIR Mappings</a> - Specifies UDS+ data elements and their FHIR Mappings and differences from US Core.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="spec.html">FHIR API Based Reporting Specification</a> - Specifies detailed requirements for the FHIR API based UDS+ data submission.
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="downloads.html">Downloads</a> - Allows downloading a copy of this implementation guide and other useful information
    </li>
  </ul>
</div>